### **SHAIKH MUBIN**

Email id : yaminmubin@gmail.com

Linkedin ID: linkedin.com/in/mubin-shaikh-364ab11b4

**Contact no.** : 8421681220

### **S**UMMARY

Hi, I am Data Science enthusiast pursuing a Master degree in Statistics. With subject expertise I am developing R and Python programming, Machine learning, Deep learning, Computer vision, NLP and Data Science. I love giving a statistical approach to problems which gives unbiased and concrete results.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

AI Engineer intern,

Oct 2021 - Present

Industry 4.0 consultancy pvt.ltd

In this internship, I had work on Deep learning, Machine learning, NLP, EDA, Clustering and Computer Vision.

Data Science intern,

Aug 2021 - Present

Data trained

In this internship, I have to fit the data into model, do the hyperparameter tuning and find the bugs/errors from ML project.

Jun 2021 - July 2021

Machine Learning Engineer Intern,

**Qubit Computer** 

The primary objective of this internship is to develop strategies. I done project on Classification problem using Decision Tree Classifier and object detection using Tensorflow.

Data Science Inter,

July 2021 – Aug 202

LetsGrowMore

In this internship I have done various project on Machine learning using KNN, Logistic Regression, SVM.

#### SKILLS

Python and R Programming.

**Machine Learning** techniques such as Regression, Classification and Time Series with mathematical understanding.

**Statistics**: Proficient statistician with expertise in Operations Research, Design of experiments, Hypothesis testing, Statistical analysis and have a statistical perspective.

**Deep Learning**: I have knowledge of Computer vision and NLP. I have done various project on ANN, RNN and CNN.

SQL: Extracting data from SQL

Basics of Java and Html.

## Courses

Complete Machine Learning with R Studio

Source: Udemy

Master in Numpy for Machine learning

Source: Udemy

Deep Learning using Keras and Pytorch

Source: Applied AI

Natural Langauage Processing(Building real world)

Source: Udemy

**Complete Introduction to SQL Programming** 

Source: Udemy

### **PROJECTS**

Amazon Customer Sentiment Analysis (2021)

Tools: Python, Logistic Regression

Analysis of Telecom Service provider (2019-2020)

**Tools:** R programming, Excel

Predict the future stock price basis on Reviews(2021)

Tools: Python, Naïve Bayes Algorithm

Predict the Strength of Passwords (2021)

Tools: Python, Logistic Regression

Old car price prediction (using Random Forest) (2021)

Tools: Python, Random Forest Regressor

A.I Assistant (JARVIS) (2020)

Tools: Python

Stock Market Analysis(2021)

Tools: python, LSTM

Object Detection by training cats and dogs images

Tools: Python, VGG16

# EDUCATION

2020 - Pursuing Masters in Statistics,

(Expected by 2022) North Maharashtra University,

Maharashtra.

78%

2017 – 2020 Bachelors of Science,

Shivaji University, Kolhapur

72.02%

2015 – 2017 A level

Rajaram College, Kolhapur

#### INTRESTS

Sports Enthusiast: Football, Badminton

Interested in: Love reading and knowing Biography of people. Playing video games, Research in Islamic Culture

Watching Stand-up Comedy.